live.
>> Like I say, welcome brothers and sisters
to another Wednesday question and answer
where we open up with the ten
commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother James,
and God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which have brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shalt have,
nor the gods before me. Thou shalt not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shalt not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I, the Lord thy God,
am a jealous God, visiting the iniquity
of the fathers upon the children unto
the third and fourth generation of them
that hate me, and showing mercy unto
thousands of them that love me, and keep
my commandments. Thou shalt not take the
name of the Lord thy God in vain. For
the Lord will not hold him guiltless
that taketh his name in vain. Remember
the Sabbath day to keep it holy. Sixth
day shalt thou labor and do all thy
work, but the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God. In it thou shalt
not do any work, thou nor thy son, nor
thy daughter, thy man's servant, nor thy
maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates. For
in six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the Sabbath day, and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor as
man's servant, nor as maid servant, nor
as ox, nor as ass, nor anything that is
thy neighbors. I read Exodus 20:es 1-17.
May the Lord add a blessing to the
reading of this word. In Jesus' name we
pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague questions
as well as the long scripture questions
and questions of debate. We are not here
to debate. We are here to spread the
true gospel of Jesus. So please be as
direct as possible with your questions
so we can be as direct as possible with
our answers out of the King James Bible.
No other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind that this is a live stream. So,
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum. But let me
introduce you to the family that's on
the panel this evening. We got brother
Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> Brother Jerome,
>> rest in peace.
>> Brother Dre.
>> Good evening. Brother James,
>> good evening everyone.
>> Sister Deborah,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Sean,
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
So, Sister Deborah, please start us off
with our first question of the program.
>> Uh, yes, there are several heldover
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A. So,
David Conurs asked you to explain Second
Kings 14 [clears throat] vers 9 and 10.
>> All right. Explanation on 2 Kings 14
verse 9 and 10. Let's go there, brother
James. And when you get there, brother,
pick it up at verse 9 and 10. And the
guest caller will take it from there.
Okay, that's 2 Kings 12:9 and 10.
>> 14. Second 14. Second Kings 14.
>> 14. Okay. verses 9 and 10 says, "And
Joash the king of Israel sent to Amziah,
king of Judah, saying, the thistle that
was in Lebanon, sent to the cedar that
was in Lebanon,
saying, Give thy daughter to my to my
son to wife, and there passed by a wild
beast that was in Lebanon, and trod down
the thistle.
Thou hast indeed smitten Eden, and thine
heart have lifted thee up, glory of
this, and tarry at home. For why
shouldest thou meddle to thy hurt, that
thou shouldest fall, even thou and Judah
with thee?
But but Amziah would not hear. Therefore
Joash the king of Israel went up and he
and Amziah king of Judah looked one
another in the face at Beth Sheamesh
which belongth to Judah and Judah
>> that's good that's good right there
brother we going to ask the guest caller
can you please shine some light on that
second Kings 14 verse 9 and 10
>> it's simple
king of uh Judah
Britain
uh invited the king of Israel
to a war and the king of Israel was
telling him you are going to use thistle
and just simply tell him look you are
inferior to me if you start a war with
against me you will lose
and he did and he lost all he's saying
so you're inferior
>> all right thank you for that. We hope
that that answered your question as we
continue to move on to our next one.
>> Next one. A Thomas wants explanation on
First Chronicles 5:es
1 through 3.
>> All right. Now, we're talking about 1
Chronicles 5:es 1-3.
Brother Jerome, share some light.
Let's go take a look at it.
Okay. 1 Chronicles 5.
>> Yeah.
>> Verses 1 through3 says, "Now the sons of
Reuben, the firstborn of Israel, for he
was the firstborn. But for as much as he
defiled his father's bed, his birthright
was given unto the sons of Joseph, the
son of Israel. And the genealogy is not
to be reckoned after the birthright.
For Judah prevailed above his brethren,
and of him came the chief ruler, but the
birthright was Joseph's. The sons, I
say, of Reuben, the firstborn of Israel,
was Hanok and Paloo and Hezron and
Carmy.
>> Yeah. So, it it pretty much means what
it says. you know, he he's telling you
that Reuben was the um firstborn and the
birthright was to go to the firstborn,
but because of what Reuben did and land
with his father's concubine, cuz we can
we can actually read that in uh Genesis
35. Uh matter of fact, go there. Um
let's go read that the Lord took the
birthight um from Reuben and gave it to
Joseph.
Okay, but let's go read that. Genesis 35
and read verse 21 and 22 I believe.
>> Okay. Genesis 35 21 and 22 say, "And
Israel journeyed and spread his tent
beyond the tower of Edo. And it came to
pass when Israel dealt in the land that
Reuben went and lay with Bahal his
father's concubine. And Israel heard
it." Now the sons of Jacob were 12.
>> Yeah. And because of that act, what we
read uh just a minute ago in that
chronicles, the Lord took the birth
right from Reuben and gave it to Joseph.
That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you, brother.
And we're going to move on to our next
question.
>> Uh next one. Brother Olus asked, "What
does Titus 1
14 and 15 mean? and what precept could
he use with it?
>> All right, so Titus 1 14 through 15.
What does that mean? And what precept
could I use with it? That's that little
book right after second Timothy. Brother
Dre, what you say?
>> Yeah, let's go to Titus 1 and read 14
through 16.
>> Okay,
>> go ahead and read it when you get it,
brother. Okay. It says, "Not giving heed
to Jewish fables and commandments of men
that turn from the truth."
>> Unto the pure all things are pure, but
unto them that are defiled, and
unbelieving is nothing pure, but even
their mind and conscience is defiled.
They profess that they know God, but in
works they deny him, being abominable
and disobedient, and unto every good
work reprobate.
So this is this is sort of
self-explanatory
as well because we talking about someone
giving heed to fables and commandments
of men that turn from the truth. John
17:17 says, "Sanctify them through thy
truth. Thy word is truth." Verse 15
says, "Unto the pure all things are
pure, but unto them that are defiled and
unbelieving is nothing pure, but their
mind and conscience is defiled." So what
what is it that is unpure to them? They
don't believe the word of God.
So, let's go over to uh Proverbs 30 and
I want to read I want you to read verses
five and six, brother James. Proverbs 30
5 and six.
>> Okay. Proverbs 30 5 and 6 says, "Every
word of God is pure. He is a shield unto
them that put their trust in him
>> and and though not unto into his words,
least he reprove thee, and thou be found
a liar. So every word of God is pure,
but to these is nothing pure.
You know, they are unbelieving.
They profess that they know God, but in
works they deny him. sound like a lot of
people not only from back then but
people today as well. Let's go to Mark
7. Mark 7.
Mark 7. And I want you to read verses
5-9.
>> Okay. Mark 7:es
5-9 say then the Pharisees and scribes
asked him why walk not thy disciples
according to the tradition of the elders
but eat bread with unwashed hands.
>> Notice it said the tradition of the
elders just like that was talking about
traditions.
Go ahead. He answered and said unto
them, "Well, hath Isaiah prophesied of
you hypocrites, as it is written, this
people honorth me with their lips, but
their heart is far from me."
>> How be it in vain do they worship me,
teaching for doctrine the commandments
of men.
For for laying aside the commandment of
God, ye hold the tradition of men as the
washing of pots and cups, and many other
such like things ye do.
>> And he said,
>> and that's it.
>> And he said unto them, full well ye
reject the commandments of God, that ye
may keep your own tradition. And that's
what they were doing back then. And
that's what a lot of people do now. And
that quote from Isaiah is Isaiah 29 and
13.
Second Timothy 4 tell you they going to
be turned to fables.
What's a fable? Sunday is the Sabbath.
What's a fable? Jesus was born December
25th. What's a fable in works? You don't
have to have no works. So the same thing
we just read in Titus, in works they
deny him being abominable and unto every
good work reprobate.
That's all I got.
>> All right. Thank you for shedding some
light on that question, brother. As we
continue to move to our next one,
>> next one. He also asks, "Why was Satan
disputing over the body of Moses?"
Why was Satan disputing or arguing over
the body of Moses? Let's go there,
brother. Let's let's pick that verse up
in that Jude 9. Jude 9, that book right
before Revelations.
Jude 9.
And when you get there,
pick it up at that verse 9.
Jude 9 and 9.
>> Okay. Yet Michael the archangel when
contending with the devil, he disputed
about the body of Moses.
>> So we see here Michael the Archangel
when contending with the devil. You know
it could have been a facetoface face off
and they talking about the body of Moses
here. Go ahead.
Durst not bring against him a railing
accusation, but said, "The Lord rebuke
thee."
>> All right. So when Satan was contending
and trying to make an argument about the
body of Moses, hey, Michael the
Archangel just said, "Hey, the Lord
rebuked thee because uh Satan is always
going against what the Lord want to do."
Like brother Dre just said. Lord say
nobody has went to heaven. They say
everybody goes to heaven. They say there
is no Sabbath day. Lord say there is. So
on and on. But let's go into uh that
Deuteronomy the 34th chapter.
>> And let's see why Michael said, "The
Lord rebuke thee." And let's bring some
closure to that question. Deuteronomy
34.
And when you get there, brother, pick it
up
at verse five and six. Because the Lord
do what he want to do cuz he got all
power. Let's see what Deuteronomy 34:5
and 6 say. Go ahead.
>> So Moses, the servant of the Lord, died
there in the land of Moab according to
the word of the Lord.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And he buried him in a valley in the
land of Moab over against Beth Pure. But
no man knoweth of his supplica until
this day. So even though we talking
about this day and this was thousands of
years ago when Moses died and when he
was buried, no man knows where he is at
even until this day. And that's the way
the Lord had it set up. That's how he
wanted it. And that's why Michael just
said the Lord rebuked thee. It's already
written that the body of Moses ain't
nobody going to know where it's going to
be at even until this day.
And that's all I got.
All right, we hope that that answered
your question as we keep on moving right
along.
>> Yes, moving on. Mo Money Waters asks,
"When Jesus come back?"
>> All right, guest caller.
>> I want to get a direct answer to that
question.
>> Okay.
>> Nobody don't nobody know why Michael was
disputing with uh uh Satan over Moses
body.
>> Okay.
book don't say
>> nobody.
>> All right.
Okay.
All right. So, we're going to move on to
our next question.
>> Next one. Mooney Waters asks, "When
Jesus come back to rule over us, where
will the lake of fire be? On earth
outside of the kingdom of heaven."
>> All right, Julius. The lake of fire.
That's a that's a good question.
And here's the answer. Let's go to
Acts the first chapter.
Got a couple of places to go here,
James. Let's read quick.
>> Okay.
>> Acts the first chapter. Let's look at
Let's pay attention to
when Jesus ascended and where he
ascended from.
Acts one and pick it up at verse 9. Read
quick. James.
>> And when he had spoken these things,
while they behind beheld, he was taken
up, and a cloud received him out of
their sight.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And while they looked steadfastly toward
heaven, as he went up, behold, two men
stood by them in white apparel,
which also said, "Ye men of Galilee, why
stand ye gazing up into heaven? This
same Jesus which is taken up from you
into heaven shall so come in like manner
as ye have seen him go into heaven.
>> Now when he left where did he leave
from? Go ahead.
>> Then returned they unto Jerusalem from
the mount called which is from Jerusalem
a Sabbath day's journey.
>> Now he left from the mount of olives and
ascended up. And the two angels said,
"The same Jesus that you see us sending,
we'll descend in like manner." Now you
ask a question. When Jesus come back,
parentheses to rule over us, where will
the lake of fire be? Let's go to
Revelation the 22nd chapter.
Bear with me. I got two places after
this. Revelation 22. Let's look at what
Let's pay attention to what Jesus said.
Revelation 22. And we got one verse
there, James. Look what Jesus said. Go
ahead.
>> Verse 12.
>> 22. Okay. Verse 12.
>> 22 and 12.
>> And behold, I come quickly and my reward
is with me to give every man according
as his work shall be.
>> I'm when I come back, I'mma bring my
reward with me to give to every man as
his work shall be. Back up to Revelation
the 19th chapter and let's look at him
when he come back.
Revelation 19 and 19. Revelation 19 and
19.
This is the beast and false prophet. Go
ahead.
>> And I saw the beast and the kings of the
earth and their armies gathered together
to make war against him that sat on the
horse and against his army.
>> Uh-huh. And the beast was taken, and
with him the false prophet that wrought
miracles before him, with which he
deceiveth them that had received the
mark of the beast, and them that
worshiped his image. These both were
cast alive into a lake of fire burning
with brimstone. That means that the lake
of fire is here on this earth. When
Jesus come, he going to bring the lake
of fire with him to give to every man as
his work shall be. Now, so the they are
going to be cast in alive, but he came
back to the mount of olives. Let's go to
the last place. Zechariah 14.
>> Zechariah 14.
The lake of fire will be here on this
earth.
Zechariah, we going to read one to four.
We going to read one and we going to
read the top of four.
>> Okay. Go ahead.
Behold, the day of the Lord cometh, and
thy spoil shall be divided in the midst
of thee.
>> Go ahead.
>> For I will gather all nations against
Jerusalem to battle, and the city shall
be taken, and the houses rifled, and the
women ravished, and half of the city
shall go forth into captivity, and the
residue of the people shall not be cut
off from the city.
>> Uh-huh. Then shall the Lord go forth and
fight against those nations as when he
fought in the day of battle.
>> So when he said he going to fight in the
day of that's the day of the Lord and
where is he going to be just the type of
for go ahead.
>> And his feet shall stand in that day
upon the mount of olives which is before
Jerusalem on the east.
>> Just like he said just like the two
angels told you he told all of us and he
told the disciples I'm leaving from the
mount of olives. I'm coming back to the
mount of olives and the mount of olives
gonna bust wide open. But when he come,
he gonna bring the mount of uh the lake
of fire with him because he gonna throw
the beast and the false prophet uh into
the lake of fire on this earth and it's
going to be here even until the father's
kingdom
around in that Jerusalem area. That's
all I got. Anybody else?
>> Let me add something to it.
>> Yes, sir.
Isaiah 66.
>> Yes sir.
>> Read verses 15 to 18. Then we going to
skip.
>> Okay. Isaiah 66
15 to 18 say for behold the Lord will
come with fire and with the char with
his chariots like a whirlwind to render
his anger with fury and his rebuke with
flames of fire. For by fire and by his
sword will the Lord plead with all
flesh, and the slain of the Lord shall
be many.
They shall sanctify themselves and
purify themselves in the gardens behind
one tree in the midst, eating swine's
flesh, and the abomination, and the
mouse shall be consumed together,
sayaeth the Lord. For I know their
works, and their thoughts. It shall come
that I will gather all nations in
tongues and they shall come and see my
glory.
>> Now all nations got to come to Jerusalem
and see the Lord's glory. Now when he
come when they come, he going to show
him something. Skip down and read verse
23 and 24.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you, guest caller.
And it shall come to pass that from one
new moon to another, and from one
Sabbath to another, shall all flesh come
to worship before me, sayaeth the Lord.
And they shall go forth and look upon
the carcasses of the men that have
transgressed against me, for their worms
shall not die, neither shall their fire
be quenched, and they shall be an
abhoring unto all flesh.
So they let you know, not only are they
going is is the lake of fire going to be
on earth, it's going to be in Jerusalem.
So everybody when they go up to worship
the Lord, which is returned to
Jerusalem, he going to tell them go over
there and look at that fire and they
going to be able to go over there in
Jerusalem and look upon these men that's
in the lake of fire.
So, it's located on this earth like
Junior said and the specific location is
going to be in Jerusalem.
That's all I have to say.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you. As we continue to move on to
our next question,
>> next one. More muddy water also asks,
"When the first resurrection happens,
how will we become gods?" It confuses me
because a god is one with all power and
that you worship. How will we be? Do you
guys have any lessons on this
gua?
>> Okay, let's go and show. First thing is
yes,
we will be God. Let's see if you make
the cut. Let's go into 1 Corinthians
15th chapter. Read verses 42- 47.
Okay. 1 Corinthians 15
42-47 say, "So also is the resurrection
of the dead. It is sown in corruption.
It is raised in corruption." In
incorruption.
It is sown in dishonor. It is raised in
glory. It is sown in weakness. It is
raised in power. It is sown a natural
body. It is raised a spiritual body.
There is a natural body and there is a
spiritual body. And so it is written,
the first man Adam was made a living
soul. The last Adam was made a
quickening spirit. How be it that was
not the first, not first, which is
spiritual, but that which is natural,
and after that which is spiritual. The
first man is of the earth, earthy. The
second man is the Lord from heaven.
So now
Adam was the first of his kind
that was
you know that was uh uh ra taken out of
the ground and made a living soul.
That's why there was no man before Adam.
Then it talks about the second man Adam
which is referring to Jesus. What you
mean the second man? Because Jesus is
the only one that was died and rose from
the dead. And when he rose from the
dead, he was no more flesh and blood. He
was spirit like all else going to become
spirit. We're going to have a spirit
body. And Jesus is God.
So that's why it's called the second
man, Adam. The first man, Adam, was man.
Second first man, Adam was man. the
second man, Adam, which uh uh uh uh was
God because Jesus rose from the dead.
Now, let's go into uh uh 1 Corinthians
15. Also, back up to verse 20
and read from 20 to 23.
Okay. Verse 1 Corinthians 15 20- 23 say,
"But now is Christ risen from the dead
and become the first fruits of them that
slept. For since by man came death, by
man came also the resurrection of the
dead. For as in Adam all die, even so in
Christ shall all be made alive.
But every man in his own order, Christ
the first fruits, afterward they that
are Christ at his coming.
>> Now, and let you know that Jesus was the
first one that rose from the dead and
became God. And the rest of them going
to come when he come and raise and uh uh
the first crop going to be what you call
the first resurrection. They will be the
same thing as Jesus is and Jesus is God.
So, how much power does Jesus have? Go
to Matthew the 20th chapter and read
verse 18.
Matthew 20
and
verse 18.
Matthew 20 and 18 says,
"Behold, we go up to Jerusalem, and the
Son of Man shall be betrayed unto the
chief priests, and unto the scribes,"
>> I'm sorry, 28
and 18.
>> Okay.
Matthew 28,
28, and 18.
It says, "And Jesus came and spake unto
them, saying, all power is given unto me
in heaven and in earth."
>> So now when Jesus come out the grave, he
wasn't man no more. He was God. So he
had all power.
It was given unto him in heaven and in
earth. Now, I'm going to give you some
advice. Uh uh uh uh uh give you
something that Paul said. Let's go into
Philippians the 2 chapter
read verses 5 and 6.
Okay.
Philippians
Philippians 2 5 and 6. Correct sir?
>> That's correct.
>> Okay. It says, "Let this mind be in you
which was also in Christ Jesus, who
being in the form of God, thought it not
robbery to be equal with God."
Now he he's saying here, I want you to
think just like Jesus think, who being
in the form of God, thought it not
robberth to be equal with God. So, not
only did Jesus have all power in heaven
and earth, he telling us that when you
come out the grave, you going to have
all power too. Therefore, that makes you
equal with God. All power. So now you
become God, you're going to have all
power
in the thing of as at the resurrection.
And then when it come to uh being
worshiped, let's see who going who
should be worshiped. Let's go into Luke
the 4th chapter
and read verse 8.
Okay. Luke 4 and verse 8 says, "And
Jesus answered and said unto him, get
thee behind me, Satan, for it is
written, thou shalt worship the Lord thy
God, in him only shalt thou serve."
Now, he didn't say, "Thou shalt worship
the Lord of thy God, and them only I
serve." He said, "In him
only thou shalt serve." Who is that?
That is talking about the father. So
when all these gods come on the scene,
still the one for them to worship is the
father. That's why when Jesus uh uh uh
told you to pray, you pray to the father
in his name. He said this is the order
you should make. Our father which are in
heaven. So even when we become God, the
only one who get all the praise is the
father and the father only. And yes,
this really God does have a lesson.
It's titled Man Created to Become God.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Tamara Williams asks, "Where
are the Egyptians of biblical times
now?"
Well, the Egyptians are biblical times
now. Brother Jerome,
>> uh the the real Egyptians, the the
ancient Egyptians, they still in Egypt.
They just not referred to as Egyptians.
You know, the Arabs when they took over
the land, they are being referred to as
Egyptians. But the real Egyptians are
are called Nubians.
You know, uh n u b i a ns. Nubians,
okay? And the Lord made them base in
that land and stuff. So, you know, when
the Arabs took took it over, they
running it. And the Egyptians is hidden
away in the land referred to as Nubians.
All right. That that's all I got if
anybody want to add.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
As we move on to our next question,
>> uh, next one. Tony Prior asks, "Is it
okay according to scripture to seek out
involve friends and family in marriage
if you're having problems?"
>> All right, let's open that up to the
panel. Is it okay according to
scriptures to seek out friends and
family if you're having marriage
problems? Let's see what the book say.
Go to Genesis 2 and 24.
Okay. Genesis 2 and 24 says, "Therefore
shall a man leave his father and his
mother and shall cleave unto his wife,
and they shall be one flesh."
Now, if he don't want you to even
involve your mother and your father, you
should not involve your friends because
that's not that's not going
to help nobody because what you're doing
is you inviting somebody else into
uh uh uh
a matter that don't belong to them. And
let me show you what what Proverbs 26
and 17 said about that.
Proverbs 26:17.
>> Okay. Proverbs 26 and17 says, "He that
passeth by and met me met me met me met
me met me met me met me met me met me
met me met meddleth with strife belongth
not to him is like one that taketh a dog
by the ears."
>> That mean they are going to get
assaulted
and they are going to get jumped.
>> Mhm.
So you don't invite your family, your
friends, and nobody into your problem.
What you do is you and your wife sit
down and you fix it. Because when you
bring any pe other people on it, it's
just like you bringing somebody into
strife that don't belong to them. Now
you going to create a lot of backbiting
and accusing and strife instead of
fixing it. It's going to get worse.
That's all I have to say.
>> Teach,
can we read that? Ephesians in the new
in the new book to back up exactly what
you just had him read in Genesis and
that Ephesians 5 31
>> and 31
it says for this cause shall a man leave
his father and mother and shall be
joined unto his wife and they too shall
be one flesh.
>> We'll have to work it out.
Mhm.
All right, we'll leave it there and move
on to our next one.
>> Next one. Jeremy Hunter asks at Ezekiel
42:13
and Ezekiel 43 verse 18, why will the
Lord require animal sacrifice in his
temple since he had already ended animal
sacrifice?
Ezekiel 42 and13 Ezekiel 43 and8 Why
will the Lord require animal sacrifice
once he has ended it? Ezekiel 42 and3
brother guest caller take it from there.
>> Okay. Ezekiel 42:13 says, "Then said he
unto me, the north chambers and the
south chambers, which are before the
separate place, they be holy chambers,
where the priests that approached unto
the Lord shall eat the most holy things.
There shall they lay the most holy
things, and the meat offering, and the
sin offering, and the trespass offering,
for the place is holy."
43 and 18
>> 43 and18 says and he said unto me, son
of man, thus sayeth the Lord God, these
are the ordinance of the altar in the
day when they shall make it to offer
burnt offerings thereon, and to sprinkle
blood thereon.
>> And the direct answer to that question
is we don't know.
All right,
>> we're going to keep it moving to our
next question. All right, next question.
Uh, yourself says, "Please explain
Leviticus 17 10 and 11. And are we
instructed anywhere in the law Old
Testament to spiritually drink blood and
eat flesh?
Brother Dre, what about spiritually
drinking blood and eating flesh,
brother? Shed some light.
>> Spiritually drinking blood and eating
flesh. And can you show in the Old
Testament? Before we go to Leviticus,
let's go to uh Isaiah 8 and we going to
read verse 20. Isaiah 8 and 20.
Read that when you get it, brother.
>> Okay. Isaiah 8:20 says to the law and to
the testimony, if they speak not
according to this word, it is because
there is no light in them. So you asking
for a Old Testament
uh scripture.
We going to speak to the law and the
testimony.
We not just speaking to one. Let's go to
Revelation 19 and 10. Then we'll go to
Leviticus.
>> Okay.
>> Revelation 19 and 10.
>> Okay. It says,
"And I fell at his feet to worship him,
and he said unto me, see thou do it not.
I am thy fellow servant and of thy
brethren that have the testimony of
Jesus. Worship God for the testimony of
Jesus is the spirit of prophecy. And
that's what the apostles testified of
what Jesus did.
And it was written in prophecy before
time. Now let's go over to Leviticus 17.
Now
>> Leviticus 17
and what was that verse? Vers 10 and Oh,
I'm sorry.
>> Verses 10 and 11. Mhm.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Go ahead and read that, brother.
>> And whatsoever man there be of the house
of Israel, or of the strangers that
sjourneth among you, that eateth any
manner of blood, I will even set my face
against that soul that eateth blood, and
will cut him off from among his people.
For the life of the flesh is in the
blood, and I have given it to you upon
the altar to make an atonement for your
souls. For it is the blood that maketh
an atonement for the soul.
And when you read in Hebrews 10, it lets
you know that the blood of bulls and
goats could never take away sin. It only
made a an an atonement for you at that
time. But there was one to come who was
to do that. But read a little bit more
of that, brother. What verse was that?
>> That was verse 11.
>> Read verse 12. And I want you to skip.
>> Therefore, I said unto the children of
Israel. No soul of yours of no soul of
you shall eat blood, neither shall any
stranger that adjornneth among you eat
blood.
>> Now, what what kind of blood is he
talking about? Read 13 and 14. Go ahead.
For whatsoever man there be of the
children of Israel, or of the strangers,
that sjorn among you, which hunteth, and
catcheth any beast or foul that may be
eaten, he shall even pour out the blood
thereof, and cover it with dust. So he's
talking about you catching, you hunting
for something, catching the beasts are
foul that may be eaten. You shall pour
out the blood thereof and cover it with
dust. Verse 14, go ahead. For it is the
life of all flesh. The blood of it is
for the life thereof. Therefore I said
unto the children of Israel, Ye shall
eat the blood of no manner of flesh. For
the life of all flesh is the blood
thereof. Whosoever eateth it shall be
cut off.
So he's talking about beast here. So
Jesus, if you go to, let's go to John 6
right quick. John 6.
John 6, pick it up at verse 53. John 6
and 53.
Go ahead, brother.
Then Jesus said unto them, "Verily,
verily, I say unto you, except ye eat
the flesh of the Son of Man, and drink
his blood, ye have no life in you." Go
ahead. Whosoever eateth my flesh, and
drinkkeeth my blood hath eternal life,
and I will raise him up at the last day.
Go ahead. For my flesh is meat indeed,
and my blood is drink indeed.
>> Now skip down to verse 60, brother, and
read that. Verse 60- 63. Go ahead.
>> Many therefore of his disciples, when
they had heard this, said, "This isn't
hard saying, who can hear it?" When
Jesus knew in himself that his disciples
murmured at it, he said unto them,
"Doeth this offend you?" What? And if ye
shall see the Son of Man ascend up where
he was before,
it is the spirit that quickenth. The
flesh profitth nothing. The words that I
speak unto you, they are spirit and they
are life.
>> And this is what he wants you to eat
that word. But also he's telling you to
eat this bread and this wine which
represents his body and his blood. But
read verse
66-68.
Go ahead. From that time many of his
disciples went back and walked no more
with him. Then said Jesus unto the twel,
"Will ye also go away?" Then Simon Peter
answered him,"Lord,
to whom shall we go, thou has the words
of eternal life?"
>> That's right. That's what we got to eat
that word. And we also got to be
obedient to that word. Let's go to last
place. Matthew 26. And I want you to
read 26-28.
>> Okay? Matthew 26 and 26-28
says, "And as they were eating, Jesus
took bread and blessed it and break it
and gave it to the disciples and said,
"Take, eat. This is my body." And he
took the cup and gave thanks and gave it
to them, saying, "Drink ye all of it.
For this is my blood of the new
testament which is shed for many for the
remission of sins. So he told you to do
this. And if you want an Old Testament
scripture, read Isaiah 53 on your own.
It tells you when you shall make his
soul an offering for sin,
you shall see his seed and he shall
prolong his days.
So I hope that helps. That's all I got.
>> All right, brother. Thank you for that
good light there as we continue to move
on with a time check.
>> Yes, the time is 8:16.
Uh Charles Johnson asks about Isaiah
56:es
3-6.
It speaks on strangers and unics in the
kingdom. would 2 Chronicles 11
15-17
and 2 Chronicles 15 verses 8- 10 be the
precepts.
>> All right, brother Julius,
>> let's let's start at his scriptures
first.
Let's start at the scriptures first.
Let's go James to 2 Chronicles 11.
Okay.
>> Because you have to uh get some
understanding uh and correlate the
scriptures.
We we're talking about different subject
matters here. 2 Chronicles James
uh 11. 2 Chronicles 11.
And when you get it, my brother, read
15-1 17.
>> Okay. 2 Chronicles 11 15-17 say, "And he
ordained him priests for the high places
and for the devil and for the calves
which he had made.
And after them out of all the tribes of
Israel, such as set their hearts to seek
the Lord God of Israel came to Jerusalem
to sacrifice unto the Lord God of their
fathers. So they strengthened the
kingdom of Judah and made Raaboam the
son of Solomon strong three years. For
three years they walked in the way of
David and Solomon.
>> So this right here is talking about
something that happened in the days of
Jeroboam and Riaboam Solomon's son.
Now let's read his let's read his 15. 2
Chronicles 15.
8 to10.
When you get it, go ahead, brother. 2
Chronicles 15 8-10. Go ahead. And when
Asa heard these words and the prophecy
of Od the prophet, he took courage and
put away the abominable idols, idols out
of the land of Judah and Benjamin, and
out of the cities which he had taken
from Mount Ephraim, and renewed the
altar of the Lord, that was before the
porch of the Lord.
And he gathered all Judah and Benjamin
and the strangers and with them out of
Ephraim and Manasseh and out of Simeon.
For they fell to him out of Israel in
abundance when they saw that the Lord
his God was with him.
>> Uhhuh.
>> So they gathered themselves together at
Jerusalem in the third month in the 15
year of the reign of Asa. So this is in
the days of King Asa and this is when um
some of the tribes of Israel lean toward
Asa the king king of Judah.
Now let's go to Isaiah the 56th chapter
because you said are these the precepts
I don't understand the precepts of what?
Isaiah 56
and let's read 3-6.
>> Okay. Well, we're going to read a little
further and we going to get the precept
of this right here. Go ahead.
>> Neither let the son of the stranger that
has joined himself to the Lord speak,
saying, "The Lord hath utterly separated
me from his people. Neither let the unic
say, behold, I am a dry tree."
>> Now, we we mentioned strangers in the
previous scripture, but you have to put
these in the right context. Go ahead.
For thus sayeth the Lord unto the Unix
that keep my Sabbaths and choose the
things that please me and take hold of
my covenant.
>> Even unto them will I give in my house
and within my walls a place and a name
better than the son than of the of sons
and of daughters. I will give them an
everlasting name that shall not be cut
off.
>> Now these are the uh these are the
units. Go ahead. units that that people
that made themselves units for the Lord.
Go ahead.
>> Also the sons of the stranger that join
themselves to the Lord to serve him and
to love the name of the Lord to be his
servants, everyone that keepeth the
Sabbath from polluting it and taking
hold of my covenant.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Even them will I bring to my holy
mountain and make them joyful in my
house of prayer. Their burn their burnt
offerings and their sacrifices shall be
accepted upon mine altar for mine house
shall be called an house of prayer for
all people. That is the precept of
Isaiah 56.
The unic and the stranger and whosoever
join themselves to the Lord will be a
part of the kingdom of God. Continue one
more verse.
The Lord God, which gathered the
outcasts of Israel, saith, yet will I
gather others to him besides those that
are gathered unto him. So now, whoever
believe on the Lord and keep his law,
statutes, and commandments,
they're going to they can become a part
of the family of God because he told
you, "My house shall be a house of
prayer for all people." That is the
precept. Your other two scriptures are
totally different. They do not
correspond to Isaiah 56 uh 3-6.
That's the best I can do, Cornell, with
the question that was asked.
>> All right. Thank you for that. As we
continue to move on, sister, to our next
question.
>> Next one. Someone said, "We are
commanded by God to go out and
evangelize,
and if we choose not to in evangelize,
we are breaking God's commandments."
Thoughts?
>> All right. Some say you're commanded to
go out and evangelize, and if you choose
not to do so, are you breaking God's
commandments? Guest caller.
>> No.
All right. So, you're not breaking God's
commandments if you decide that you do
not want to go out and evangelize.
All right, Sister Deb, are we taking a
trip into new territory?
>> Yes, we are. We are now into tonight's
Q&A for Wednesday, May the 27, 2026.
Uh Shanquilla Au jobi says, "Last week I
asked about a non-believer
who claims there's no historical trace
of Jesus family in today's world. He
wants a specific name to check
connections.
Is there someone I can mention?
Let's open that up to the panel.
You have something for that
questionnaire, guest caller.
>> Yeah. Do some research and find it
yourself.
>> All right.
>> Okay. We're going to move on to our next
question.
>> Next one. Skywriter says, "How do we
know the Mi are the Russians? I looked
it up. They don't support that idea."
All right. The Mi being the Russians.
Let's open that up also to the panel.
>> Same thing. Research is there. And
research the scripture, too. Get it to
you.
Okay,
>> our next question.
>> Yeah, he also says, "Persians are
Gentiles. What was their lineage,
>> the sons of Jap?"
All you got to do is go into Genesis the
10th chapter, run it down, get the names
and and and and and uh you can match the
modern the modern day name with them and
you'll come up with who is saying uh uh
uh who they are. Go to Genesis the 10th
chapter like the brother said and the
sons of JF
and you can connect every name
then you will find out who the m and the
pers are too.
And they still together today.
>> Russia and Iran.
>> That's right. Been together since the
fall of Babylon.
>> Yep. All right. That's your homework
assignment. Okay. Let's move on to our
next one.
>> Ah, next one. Be alert as can you please
explain Ezekiel 7 verse 20. What
ornament is this scripture referring to?
Um,
with the spelling, so I don't know what
word he's trying to say there. He says,
"Can you explain Ezekiel 7 verse 20?
What ornament
is this scripture referring to?"
>> All right, let's go there, brother. and
let's open it up to the panel. He wants
to know that verse 20, but let's pick it
up. Read 19 and 20. And then let's open
it up to the panel.
>> Okay. Ezekiel 7 19 and 20 say, "They
shall cast their silver in the streets,
and their gold shall be removed. Their
silver and their gold shall not be able
to deliver them in the day of wrath of
the Lord.
They shall not satisfy their souls,
neither fill their boughs, because it is
the stumbling block of their iniquity.
>> As for the beauty of his ornament, he is
set as majesty. She said it in majesty,
but they made the images of their
abominations and of their detestable
things therein. Therefore have I set it
far from them.
Mhm.
>> So, they want to know what ornament is
this scripture referring to?
>> All right. Open to the panel. We know um
the Lord wasn't with it. It's
abomination according to that 20th
verse.
>> I don't have a clue. All right, we're
gonna leave it right there, Sister
Deborah, as we fire off our next
question.
>> Yes. Leap Leaping Lamb says,
"If the wages of sin is death, how can
there be a sin not unto death?"
He gives or they uh whoever uh is male
or female. First John 5 verse1 17.
Sin is sin. Correct.
>> All right, let's go there. First John
five.
And we'll open up to the panel there,
brother James, after you read that.
First John five.
And the question is
about
sin. First John 5
and 17.
Go ahead, brother.
Uh, you on mute, brother.
It says all unrighteousness is sin, and
there is a sin not unto death.
>> All right, let's open up to the panel.
Have a little light shed on that
question.
Go
>> to Matthew 12th chapter.
There is a sin that is not unto death.
And there's a sin that is also to unto
death.
Ask the question again, Debbie.
>> Yes. If the wages of sin is death, how
can there be a sin not unto death?
>> Because the Lord said there's a sin that
is not unto death. Matthew 12.
Matthew 12, James,
pick it up at verse 31.
>> It says, "Wherefore I say unto you, all
manner of sin and blasphemy shall be
forgiven unto men, but the blasphemy
against the Holy Ghost shall not be
given unto men."
>> shall not be forgiven.
>> Oh, forgiven. Shall not be forgiven unto
men.
>> Uhhuh. Go ahead.
>> And whatsoever speaketh a word against
the Son of man, it shall be forgiven
him. But whosoever speaketh against the
Holy Ghost, it shall not be forgiven
him, neither in this world nor either in
the world to come.
>> That's because uh the Lord said this sin
cannot be forgiven. blasphem against the
against the Holy Spirit,
knowing the word and teaching it
falsely.
And uh sometimes you could sin
inadvertently. You repent and you could
be forgiven. He told you all manner of
sin at verse 31 shall be forgiven unto
men.
Yeah. And and also if you um if you know
what the truth is and you tell a lie,
hey, you gonna be in big trouble with
the Lord.
>> Hey, can we read um Ezekiel 18?
>> Ezekiel 18.
>> Yeah,
>> there you go.
>> And read verse 27 and 28.
>> There you go, Ro.
>> Okay. Ezekiel 18 27 and 28. Say again,
when the wicked man hath turned away
from his wickedness that he hath
committed, and doeth that which is
lawful and right, he shall save his soul
alive.
Because he considerth and turneth away
from all his transgressions that he has
committed, he shall surely live, he
shall not die.
Yeah. Yes, sir. Can we read that 26
since we here, too?
26 says, "When a righteous man turneth
away from his righteousness, and
committh iniquity, and dieth in them,
for his iniquity that he hath done,
shall he die."
>> Yep. So, all right. We
>> go ahead guess caller.
whole thing in a nutshell is
the wage of sin is death as if you
continue to sin and on purpose. Go to uh
Hebrews 10
26 and 7.
>> Okay. Hebrews 10 and:26 says,
"For if we sin willfully after that we
have received the knowledge of the
truth, there remain remainth no more
sacrifice for sins."
>> Mhm.
>> Go ahead.
>> But but a certain fearful looking for of
judgment and fiery indignation which
shall devour the adversaries.
>> Yes. So the way of sin is that. But when
you stop sinning and you repent and turn
to the Lord, then you ain't said it no
more
>> because you have stopped.
So you won't face death.
That's all I have to say.
>> And on your own on your own, read first
John 5 and 16 on your own.
>> Exactly.
All right, sister.
>> Let's go, James. Let's go and read it,
James.
First John 5 and 16.
>> Yeah.
>> It says, "If any man see his brother sin
a sin, which is not unto death, he shall
ask, and he shall give him life for them
that sin, not unto death."
>> Because he repented. Go ahead.
>> There is a sin unto death. I do not say
that he shall pray for it.
>> And that sin unto death is blasphemy
against the Holy Spirit. as we read in
Matthew 12:31.
That's all I got. Cornell, thank you
guys for calling.
>> All right, we're going to keep it
moving, Sister Deborah.
>> All right. Uh, this person is confused,
but uh, Charlotte T says, "I understand
that night comes before day." So if day
begins and then he have slash ends at
sundown
when it's dark.
How do you explain Matthew 28 1-6
Mark 16 1 and 2 le Luke 24
1-37
which seems to indicate that Mary came
to Jesus suppl
to find him gone after the Sabbath early
in the morning on the first day. Does
this not also imply that Jesus could
have risen Sunday night, first day?
>> No,
because you said the first day of the
week. Go to go to St. John 20 and start
reading at verse one. Okay.
St. John 20 and1 says, "The first day of
the week cometh Mary Magdalene early
when it was yet dark unto the supplica
and seen the stone taken away from the
supplica."
Now he say come early while it was yet
dark.
First day of the week started when the
sun went down
on the uh uh uh on the Sabbath day which
is called Saturday.
And so now once the Sabbath day is over
with, once the uh Sabbath day is over
with, when the sun go down, then they
went and look for it to tell you right
now that they rested until the Sabbath
day was over with. Can somebody go and
read that?
>> All right, we're in search mode for
that.
Say while it was still dark,
first day of the week started at sundown
Saturday evening.
Is that Luke 23?
>> Oh yeah.
>> 23:55.
>> Okay.
Luke 23 and 55 says, "And the women also
which came with him from Galilee
followed after and beheld the supplica
and how his body was laid."
>> Go ahead. And they and they returned and
prepared spices and ointments and rested
the Sabbath day according to the
commandment.
>> Go ahead.
>> Oh, that that ends chapter 23. So then
chapter 24:1 says, "Now upon the first
day of the week, very early in the
morning, they came into the supplica
bringing the spices which they are
prepared and certain others with them.
And they found the stone rolled away
from the supplicant and they entered in
and
found that he was gone. But the previous
chapter let you know they rested on the
Sabbath day.
They couldn't go and do nothing until
the Sabbath day is over with. So when
the Sabbath day was over with, they went
early the first day of the week. Now,
early could be either way it go, but the
whole thing is it was still dark.
If the sun went down at 8:00,
they could have went there at 8:05. It
was the first day of the week.
Or they could have went at 9
05 or they could have went at 5:00 in
the morning. Either way it was, it was
still dark.
>> Yep.
>> And Jesus didn't rise on the first day
of the week. They tell you he was gone.
That's all I got to say.
>> All right. Hope that answered your
question. Next one.
>> Next one. Kenya Hayes asks in Matthew 3
verse 11. Can you explain
what is the fire and is the fire true?
3 and 11.
All right.
>> Yes. Matthew 3 verse 11.
>> Pick it up at 10. James read 10 and 11.
Matthew 3:es 10 and 11. Say, "And now
also the axes laid unto the root of the
trees. Therefore, every tree which
bringeth not forth good fruit is heuned
down and cast into the fire.
I indeed baptize you with water unto
repentance, but he that cometh after me
is mightier than I, whose shoes I am not
worthy to bear. He shall baptize you
with the Holy Ghost and with fire.
>> That's word of God.
>> This is This is Jesus coming. He going
to baptize you with the word of God. And
if you don't repent, he going to baptize
you with the fire, the lake of fire.
>> All right.
>> Jeremiah said that word that word was
like fire shut up in his bones.
>> Yeah, but we ain't talking about that.
>> Okay.
>> What he's talking about is baptizing you
with the lake of fire.
>> You don't want that.
That's for sure. All right.
It's the word of Jesus that's going to
save you. And if you don't listen to it,
then Jesus is the one going to cast you
into the lake of fire. Who cast the
beast and prophet into the lake of fire?
>> Jesus.
>> Simple as that.
>> All right, take heed as we move on to
our next question.
>> Uh, next one. St. Stacy Jones asks, "Why
don't we use the Apocrypha?"
>> All right. Why don't we use the
Apocrypha?
Does it match up with the book that we
are reading from now? Go right ahead and
open it up to the panel.
>> Anybody that asked that question have
not read the Apocrypha.
>> Yeah. Because if you read the apocrypha,
you tell you see that is contrary to the
word of God. But again too is nothing
that authenticate where the apo who
wrote the apocrypha. It certainly was
written by Israel.
And the book tell you uh uh uh in the
ninth chapter of Romans Israel belong
the the uh giving of the law the
adoption and the service of God. in your
Romans the third chapter that the
articles of God, articles of God's in
the hand of Israel. So this apocrypha,
there is nothing that shows that it's
written by the Hebrews. In fact, if you
really research, it'll tell you that it
was written by people other than the
Hebrew Israelite.
>> That's right.
>> If you read the Apocrypha, you would
even ask that question.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> All right. as we continue to move along.
>> Um, would you believe, brother, um, that
was the last question?
>> Oh, all right. That was the last
question. Okay, we finally got y'all. We
done ran out of questions, [laughter]
>> right? And the time is 8:42.
>> 8:42. All right. Well, on that note, we
are going to thank everybody as we clock
out early who tuned in with us this
evening. We want to thank you all from
all around the world. And we want to say
that until we all come together again,
please be safe out there, stay prayed
up, be blessed, and may the Lord have
mercy on us all as brother James closes
us out with an early evening brother.
Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name. Thy kingdom come,
>> thy will be done in earth as it is in
heaven. Give us this day our daily
bread, and forgive us our debts as we
forgive our debtors, and lead us not
into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the
power, and the glory forever. In Jesus'
name we pray. Amen.